ANTHONY CHIDI NNAMCHI

Contact Address: No. 4 Churchill Enahoro Street, Gbazango Extension, Kubwa, Abuja

Tel: +234(0)7030852400, +234(0)7017131822

Email: nnamchianthony@yahoo.com, nnamchitony@gmail.com

LinkedIn Url: https://www.linkedin.com/in/anthony-nnamchi-680663120/

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I have enjoyed over 11 years of overall work experience and have thrived in challenging organisations where information technology, human resource management, administration, sales and marketing, engineering, technical and cognitive skills have been maximized to meeting organisational goals.

SKILLS

- ➤ Good at React.js, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, PHP, Python, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, Git and GitHub
- ➤ Good at Corel Draw, Photoshop, Canva, Figma, etc
- Proficient in website development using WordPress
- ➤ Google Cloud Platform Trainee
- Proficiency in Microsoft Office Suites
- > Attention to details
- > Excellent data collection and report writing skills
- Quality understanding of patient data confidentiality principles
- > A good team player with good interpersonal skills
- ➤ Good verbal and written communication skills in English and Pidgin English Languages

EDUCATION

2022	Master of Engineering: Chemical Engineering Federal University of Technology, Minna, Niger State, Nigeria.
2014	Bachelor of Engineering: Chemical Engineering Nnamdi Azikiwe University, Awka, Anambra State, Nigeria.
2009	Ordinary National Diploma: Chemical Engineering Institute of Management & Technology, Enugu, Enugu State, Nigeria.
2005	West Africa Senior Secondary School Certificate Community Secondary School, Neke, Enugu State.
1999	Primary School Leaving Certificate Public Primary School, Neke, Enugu State

WORK HISTORY_

09/2016 to Present

Administrative/Software Manager

LUMEN-DEO REALITIES AND CONSTRUCTIONS LTD - Utako, Abuja

- > Created a system for the adequate management of staff, administrative data and their updates and also, management and update of personnel and files.
- ➤ Declined cost of management by 12% through labour reduction by the creation of electronic database systems.
- ➤ Have lead a team of software technicians in building websites.
- ► Human development in administration and computer applications and operations.
- ➤ Kick-started a platform to manage staff to ensure that all opening and/or closing procedures are being followed.
- Managed and executed marketing programs and general business solutions resulting in increased company exposure, customer traffic, and sales.
- Received a promotion, from a Senior Assistant to the Director to an administrative manager, in less than 9-months.
- Put in place a policy for tracking inventory and researching discrepancies while developing a map to track clients for both positive and negative feedback.

04/2016 to 08/2016 Admin Officer/Software Engineer AVASTONE GLOBAL SERVICES LTD – Garki, Abuja

- ➤ Amplified the marketability of the company's properties by creating high interest flyers to advertise available properties to prospective clients.
- > Increased customer management, service and care utilizing personnel improved training on the use of Microsoft Word, Excel, and PowerPoint.
- > Eradicated the errors and occasions of lost data made often with manual data storage by creating electronic databases for clients.
- Maintained an 87% satisfaction rating over a 4-week period as an administrative officer.
- ➤ Reduced time spent on inventory by 20% by reorganizing physical storage of supplies.
- > Went above my duties as office administrator to implement a filing system for human resources, organizing more than 300 past and current employee documents.
- ➤ Digitized company's internal filling system of more than 5,000 files.
- > Set up and trained staff of 3 on how to use Microsoft Access platform for data management purposes.

09/2014 to 03/2016 **Station Manager**

CEN-STRONG NIGERIA LTD - Omor, Anambra State

- Maintained the administrative staff by conducting staff recruitment, selection, orientation, training and development.
- > Condensed the power and time spent on periodic reports on sales and expenditures by introducing electronic reporting methods.
- > Created an extensive marketing plan that gave the leverage to exceed retail sales goals by an average of 13% every quarter in 2014 and 2015.
- ➤ Declined monthly costs by 15% over 14months.
- Raised employee retention rates by 50% over a 2-year period by implementing an employee motivation system without any negative effect on the monthly budget and organizing a weekly prayer session.
- > Reduced the cost of equipment maintenance by 17.7% through adequate management and maintenance of company equipment and machineries.
- > Grew core customers' list by 40% in 8 months without expanding the monthly budget.
- > Introduced a bi-weekly meeting with 9 other department heads to discuss goals, updates, and challenges, and achieved increased productivity across departments by 20%.
- > Received a promotion, from a branch manager to a general manager, in less than 12-months.

04/2013 to 11/2013 **Legal Secretary**

CRIME VICTIMS FOUNDATION (CRIVIFON) LIMITED BY GUARANTEE - Garki, Abuja

- > Prepared and managed correspondence, reports and documents.
- > Organized and coordinated meetings, conferences, travel arrangements.
- > Took, typed and distributed petitions to different quarters, and handled incoming emails, mail and other material.
- Maintained schedules and calendars, arranged and confirmed appointments.
- > Organized internal and external events, and operated office equipment and managed office supplies.
- > Set up and maintained document management systems while performing other numerous secretarial duties.

09/2009 to 09/2010 **Laboratory Assistant**

PYMOTECH RESEARCH CENTRE AND LABORATORY - Abakpa-Nike, Enugu

- > Reduced the workload on the laboratory attendants by 15% within 14 days at work.
- > Strived to always meet deadlines on any job by working extra hours.
- > Created a boost on the integrity and reputation of the laboratory by always reporting to the CEO any attempt by the laboratory attendants to manipulate data during research works and data collection.
- > Introduced the use of design expert software for data analysis thereby optimizing time factor.
- > Assumed the function of the data analyst, always, by using Response Surface Methodology to analyse all data collected in his absence.
- ➤ Improved safety by adequately monitoring research students, making sure they adhered to the laboratory safety precautions.

01/2006 to 10/2007 ICT Officer KRISINTEL COMPUTERS – New-Haven, Enugu

- > Trained fresh and returning students on the basic concepts and principles of computer science.
- > Introduced and led a team of 3 employees for regular training and development of all the staff for adequate customer service provision.
- > Reduced the duration for the students training by 20% with increased students productivity through regular observation and evaluation of students' performance.
- ➤ Gave hands-on training on Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Publisher, Access, Corel Draw, AutoCad and Internet Explorer to over 175 adult students.
- > Developed lesson plans, instructional materials and other strategies to ensure that every student has a thorough knowledge of the subject.
- Produced highly trained computer intellectuals through the introduction of regular student progress check.

CAREER DEVELOPMENT ENGAGEMENTS_

- **2022 Certificate of Training Completion** of Business Management From **TONY ELUMELU FOUNDATION** (an online business management course)
- **2021 Certificate of Completion** of Learn React Course From **CODECADEMY** (an online tech course)
- **2021 Certificate of Completion** of Learn the Basics of Regular Expressions Course From **CODECADEMY** (an online tech course)
- **2021 Certificate of Completion** of Learnable internship on Front End Web Development From **GENESYS TECH HUB** (*supported by Circle Africa*)
- **2021 Certificate of Course Completion** of Google Africa Developer Training Program From **GOOGLE** (*GADS2020 an online tech course*)
- **2019 Certificate of Achievement** on Energy Transition Innovation towards Low-Carbon Future From **IFP SCHOOLS** (*supported by Total Foundation and Tuck Foundation*)
- **2019 Certificate of Completion** of Research Ethics Training Curriculum Second Edition From **FHI 360** (An online course on research ethics)
- **2016 Certificate of Proficiency** Human Resources and Skills Acquisition Programme From **HOREBSON RESOURCES** (*NYSC Secretariat, Awka, Anambra State*)
- **2005 Certificate of Proficiency** in Computer Operation From **PACKAGE COMPUTERS** (*No. 32 Okpara Avenue, Enugu State*)